your mother As a Citizen of the Russian
твоя мама Как Гражданка Российской
Federation Yes, you and others made sure
Федерации Да ты и другие сделали так
that these refugees ran away from their
чтобы эти беженцы убежали из своих
homes and your mother thinks wait no Look and
домов и мама счита подожди нет Смотри и
Mom also you think that she seems
Мама ещё тыа считаешь что она кажется
hypocritical I
это лицемерно я
understand Great Hello You are 18 years old and you
понял Здорово Здравствуйте Вам 18 лет
communicate about everything Well  about
есть есть а чём общаетесь обо всём Ну о
politics, too. It’s funny, in my opinion, sometimes
политике тоже Забавно по-моему иногда
you’re a politician or whoever. No,
бывает вы политики или кто
you’re not a politician either, that’s right, a
Нет вы же тоже не политик правильно
politician,
политик
but political activity of some kind of
а политическую деятельность какую-то
department.
депу
Yes, it seems to me, it seems to me that you’re only
Да мне кажется мне кажется только сбор
collecting donations for the ZSU, who are you, what
на зсу собираете донатами вы кто
nationality are you studying to become a
национальности на кого учитесь усь на
translator, what what
переводчика что что
translate from Russian into English I will
переводите с русского на английский буду
translate As soon as I finish the windows I need to
переводить Как закончу окон мне надо с
translate from Pay to private Well, why don’t you
Pay на приват перевести Ну это че
contact me And the question is where do you study in
обращайтесь А вопросик где учитесь в
Yurga, whose
Юргу чей
Crimea is such
Крым так
a little
такой ющий немножко
question from the point of view from the point of view of
вопрос с точки зрения с точки зрения
what point of view
какой точки зрения
you are, well, I think it’s very dense there
тебя ну там помоему очень плотно
Russian
Российская
power relative to Russian, that is,
власть отно русский то есть
occupied by Russia, there is now an established
Россией там сейчас устоявшаяся
Russian government. That's what I can
Российская власть Вот что я тебе могу
tell you. That's when there was standing
сказать Вот когда в к было стоящая
Nazi power during the Nazi
нацистская власть во время нацистской
occupation, it turns out that he was
оккупации это что он был
German, so yes, I understood, and
немецкий получается так да понял а
now it's occupied by Russia. Now I understand,
сейчас оккупирована Росси е теперь понял
Yes, I definitely understood  compare Russia
Да понял те обязательно сравнить Россию
With fascist Germany otherwise you won’t understand
С фашистской Германией иначе не поймёшь
with Nazi with Nazi no difference
с нацистской с нацистской без разницы
The difference is good there is everything So we
Разница есть хорошо есть всё Вот и
talked and compared everything the analogy is super
поговорили сравнили всё аналогия супер у
you still have some question Well, how
тебя ещё какой-то Вопрос есть Ну как
do you treat Russians badly in general
вообще к россиянам относишься
Why is it a difficult
Почему сложный
question from the point of view of which country
вопрос с точки зрения какой страны
to say  not from your personal point of view, from
сказать не с лично твоей точки зрения с
my point of view, yes Well, look, since
моей точки зрения да Ну смотри поскольку
Russian power has now been established in Crimea,
в Крыму сейчас установилась Российская
so
власть поэтому
I have a negative attitude towards
я негативно отношусь к
Russians, wait, because of the actions of the authorities. That
россиянам подожди из-за действий власти
is, you are ordinary towards Russians. It’s bad
То есть ты к россиянам обычны Плохо отно
that somehow this is irrational, so Stop,
что как-то это нерационально пому Стоп А
wait  you have power Where does it come from,
подожди у вас власть Откуда берётся вот
you, as a lawyer, did you Russians elect
ты как человек юрист вы россияне избира
power or did your power fall from the sky and
власть или у вас власть упала с неба и
seize the
захватила
Russians Well Vla Now no one chooses, it
россиян Ну Вла Сейчас никто не выбирает
seems, in Russia just like they don’t choose elections,
вроде бы в России как не выбирает выборы
even you think there were fair
даже ты считаешь что были справедливые
elections, I know, I know, I  I didn’t see that anyone
выборы знаю я знаю я не видел что кто-то
there was against it, I don’t know, I don’t mind, I’m
там против этого был не знаю я не сри я
not very interested in Russian politics,
сильно российской политикой не
I see you have elections,
интересуюсь я вижу у вас есть выборы
which means you elected you. Well, no one
значит вы избрали ви Ну Никто не
is protesting against this. Well, it seems to me that they are not
митингует против этого Ну мне кажется не
protesting because they can be imprisoned. It
митингует потому что сажать может быть
seems to me  Come on, why
Вот мне кажется А давай так с чего я
should I treat Russians well, I
должен хорошо относиться к россиянам вот
can’t
не могу
understand, I never said that, well,
понять я никогда такого не говорил ну
Russians, Russians are going to fight in Ukraine,
россияне россияне идут воевать в Украину
Russians support those who are fighting in
россияне поддерживают ээ тех кто воюет в
Ukraine, Russians just live there, pay
Украину россияне просто живут там платят
taxes and that’s it, and for this money they go shorter than a
налоги и всё и за эти деньги идут короче
rocket  flying to Ukraine Well, how about you
ракеты летят в Украи Ну как бы так ты
too, you generally collect money, your
тоже ты вообще собираешь деньги твоей
activity is to collect money
деятельностью является собирать деньги
for missiles, the same thing, yes, well,
на ракеты то же самое да да ну у меня
look at me, it’s different. For example, I’m going to kill
смотри разное Например я собираю убивать
people with missiles, so good Yes, look, I’m
людей ракетами поему хоро Да смотри я
collecting money for drones there for all sorts of things
собираю деньги на дроны там на всякое
for people  who came to our country
чтобы людей которые пришли в нашу страну
to kill us is a sacred thing, but to
убивать нас это священное дело а
help someone get into a foreign country, to
помогать кому-то залезть в чужую страну
kill is a sin, that’s all a believer No,
убивать это грех вот и всё верующий Нет
not a believer Well, okay then it’s clear Well,
не верующий Ну ладно тогда понятно Ну
look, everything is very simple That is, for example,
смотри очень всё просто То есть например
when a policeman and a bandit, a bandit
когда Полицейский и бандит бандит
shoots at a policeman This  it’s bad a
стреляет в полицейского Это плохо
policeman shoots a bandit, it’s a
полицейский стреляет в бандита это
medal, it’s true.
медаль правда
Yes, and here the occupier came to kill us on
Да Так и Тут оккупант пришёл убивать на
our land, that’s bad, he’s a bastard
нашей земле нас это плохо он [__]
terrorist when they kill him.
террорист когда его убивают Это хорошо
that what I’m telling you is that the occupiers in
что те тебе рассказываю Да оккупанты по
Kharkov are flying in from the Belgorod
Харькову прилетают из Белгородской
region, the entire Belgorod region is
области вся Белгородская область
military, there are a lot of military units of
милитари Зро там куча военных частей
military units, and they’re flying along them, because
военных подразделений вот по ними идт
somewhere there’s something that does
прилёт то что там где-то что-то бывает
n’t reach, somewhere, something kills you and
не долетает где-то что-то ваше убивает и
In short, yours will die. Well, sometimes contact the
дохнут короче ваши Ну бывает обращайтесь
Russian troops. Let them leave the
вот к российским войскам Пусть они уйдут
Belgorod region and not
из Белгородской области пола и не будут
fly in. Everything is simple, as if not,
прилетать Вот Всё просто ну как бы нет
well, you just somehow arrange in your
ну ты просто какими-то как вот у себя в
head what is right and what
голове устраиваешь что правильно что
is wrong in some general way
неправильно ты какими-то общими
principles of morality general principles of morality
принципами морали общий принципы морали
look we are defending ourselves we are right So you are
смотри мы защищаемся мы правы Так что вы
there morally some girl
там морально какую-нибудь девочку
who is sitting in the house playing Nobody
которая то сидит в доме играет Никто
Nobody is shooting Let’s say something like Strelna
Никто же не стреляет Давай типа Стрельне
in Belgorod It didn’t reach
в Белгороде говор что-то Не долетела
anything terrible so nothing terrible
ничего страшного так ничего страшного
died an innocent girl died  war
умерла невинная девочка умерла война да
and that’s all And what can you do they shot
и всё И что сделаешь стреляли
at Well, it’s impossible to shoot because they’re
по Ну как не получается стрелять потому
shooting at us from there,
что оттуда по нам стреляют приходится
so Russia needs to, so you
стрелять поэтому России надо вот ты
have to come out in your city Yes, with
должен выйти в своём городе Да с
the demand to take little girls from the
требованием забрать маленьких девочек из
Belgorod region so that they can be taken
Белгородской области чтобы их завезли
somewhere else, for example
где-то в другой например в оренбургскую
they settled in boarding houses in the Orenburg region Yes, in
область там в пансионатах поселили Да в
Orsk in Orenburg, for example, they now
Орск в Оренбург например там сейчас
say that the resorts are good Yes, so that the
говорят что курорты хорошие Да вот чтобы
Belgorod girls do not suffer since the
белгородские девочки не страдали раз
Russian troops are there again, some kind of dream about
русские войска туда опять какая-то сно
some kind of tragedies or something in
на с какими-то трагедиями что ли в
Russia, well, yes, well  that no,
России ну есть Да ну а что нет смотри я
look, everything is very simple Just and business, uh, I
оче всё очень просто Just и бизнес ээ я
understand that the more
понимаю что чем больше в России
disasters of some kind in Russia, Russia
катастроф каких-то тем у России меньше
will have less human resources,
будет человеческих ресурсов ээ
financial and technical, for Ukraine. That
финансовых и технических на Украину То
is, now a lot of money, people and equipment
есть сейчас куча денег людей и техники
will need to be thrown at the restoration of the
нужно будет кинуть на восстановление
Orenburg  regions and so on, that
Оренбургской области и так дальше то
is, these people will not do anything somewhere
есть Эти люди не будут где-то что-то
in Ukraine,
делать в Украине
this equipment will not dig some
эта техника не будет копать какие-то там
trenches there, they will not transport anything to
траншеи не будет что-то подвозить на
the front and this money will not fly to Ukraine,
фронт и эти деньги не полетят в Украину
everything is simple, that’s why it’s  first, different
всё просто поэтому это во-первых разный
budgets, secondly, they are incomparable in
бюджет во-вторых они несравнимые по
scale, some billions of
масштабам это какие-то миллиарды
dollars
долларов
go absolutely when it’s right when we
идут абсолютно когда прально когда мы
collect 100 Drones there, we collected a
собираем там 100 Дронов мы собрали вот
million
миллион
hryvnia, 100 Drones in terms of war, yes,
гривенко 100 Дронов в плане войны это да
but with the help of them there are 100,300 shorter than
но там с помощью них там 100 300 короче
some  this is plus drop by drop And everything is
каких-то это плюс капля по капле И всё
like that and here you understand that the budget in terms of the
так и тут понимаешь да бюджет в плане
overall budget is not enough, but there are few
общего бюджета это мало но там мало там
Tajiks there, in short, there in Belgrade,
таджики погуляли короче там в Белграде
everything is there and it all adds up, the budget and
там всё и оно всё складывается бюджет и
everything becomes shorter than a hole, as if people are already in
всё стаёт короче дырки как бы люди уже в
Orenburg shouting What  like they
Оренбурге кричат А что типа в Мариуполе
built something there in Mariupol And
там что-то построили А нам по 20.000
they gave us 20,000 each for flooded houses, well, there’s not much there, just let’s
выдали за затопленные дома ну там мало
get back to the conversation, I do
просто к разговору всё-таки вернёмся я
n’t understand this Well, as ideologists,
вот не понимаю такой Ну как идеологи
such schadenfreude like, well, it won’t get there. It’s
такое злорадство типа ну не долетит
okay, what’s good about the fact
Ничего страшного что же хорошего в том
that we  don’t look, I’m generally a very
что проы ми не смотри я вообще очень
kind, good-natured person until I was
добры добродушный человек был до
fourteen in the fourteenth year I
четырнадцатого года в четырнадцатом году
grew up a little,
у меня Я немножко повзрослел у меня
some let’s say a little
какие-то скажем немножко
dehumanization happened, but I held on
расчеловечивание произошло но Я держался
I held on I kind of made a show of myself
Я держался я как бы там са мановение
in two second year I passed I
делал в два втором году у меня прошли я
passed  transformation training
прошёл тренинг трансформации вот в
was signed up in February,
феврале был записался
I went to bed, you know, with the
я лёг спать ещё таки знаешь со
suffering, the
страдальческом
dehumanization was completely gone. For
расчеловечивание очень сильно пропало Я
example, I even tried when there were
например я даже пробовал когда вот были
shellings of Belgorod. I sat down to
обстрелы Белгорода Я садился вот
meditate on, say, compassion, I
медитацию на скажем на сострадание я
tried,
пробовал
uh, to enter into the position of the residents of Belgorod and
ээ войти в положение жителей Белгорода и
understand what we say  they feel bad, they suffer
понять что скажем им плохо они страдают
and couldn’t. I can’t, you know, I can’t
и не мог Вот не не могу знаешь вот не
understand. This is the Kundalini, in short, it
могу понять Вот это Кундалини короче оно
doesn’t
не
rise all now, there was a flood in
поднимается всё сейчас вот потоп был в
Orsk and Well, as it was,
Орске и Ну как был есть вот
today I went to our place. Sunny, I
сегодня поехал у нас было Солнышко я
sat and seemed to meditate, too.  there,
сидел и как бы медитировал тоже что тамм
let me have the sun, let everyone
пусть вот у меня солнце пусть у всех
have a good time, like, well, they’re people, they’re
будет хорошо типа Ну они же люди Они же
not to blame, we’re all people, yeah, like, all the
не виноваты мы все люди Да Типа все
earth, then it started to rain
земля потом у нас пошёл дождь
and I have some kind of
и у меня какая-то вот
gloating from Orenburg, he and his window
злорадство из Оренбурга он и у него окно
is open, he says  damn it’s raining, it’s already
открыто он говорит бля дождь валит уже
pouring, I heard that in Orenburg it’s raining there,
ливень я услышал что у него в Оренбурге
it’s raining there, then I know
дождь валит у них же там потом я знаешь
that my Kundalini
вот воспр моё Кундалини так
has risen to the upper chakras, and in the
поднялось к верхним чакрам я вот в
Ukrainian language there’s a good phrase,
украинском языке есть тако хорошая фраза
zatova, breath,
затова подых зал дыхание
I’m so
Я настолько
inspired, as if here I am  I really
воодушевить как бы вот я действительно я
caught myself saying that I don’t know, maybe
поймал себя на том что я не знаю может
it’s some kind of solar
это какая-то мне кажется солнечной
meditation, it seems to me, after all. Better look, this is
медитации всё-таки Лучше смотри это
some kind of psychological disorder. I
какое-то психологическое расстройство Я
think that later how will it all end?
думаю что потом как это всё закончится
Yes, we will figure out what it was that we had
Да мы будем разбираться что же это у нас
such disorders  but now I
такие расстройства были но сейчас я
can’t do anything about it I wish there was
ничего не могу с этим поделать Я желаю
more rain in the Orenburg region I
больше дождя в Оренбургской области Я
want the houses there to be flooded in short in
хочу чтобы затопило там дома короче
general so that there would be more disasters
вообще пря так чтоб больше бедствий было
I don’t know what’s happening to me if it’s like
я не знаю что со мной делается если как
a disorder it’s a pity it’s probably hard in
растройство это жалко наверное тяжело в
such a situation it’s very very hard  yes
такой ситуации сильно очень тяжело да
Because there are some missiles flying,
Потому что тут какие-то ракеты летают
something like air raids, so I wanted to
что-то воздушные тревоги вот я хотел
meditate. Why wasn’t I from the copper here
медитировать Почему не я с меди тут
the sound of the alarm, you’re knocking you out of
звук повитряна тревога ты сбиваешь с
meditation, you can’t tune your
медитации не можешь настроить своё
internal Kundalini and I see that
внутренне Кундалини и я смотрю что вот
this is what we’ll say, a desire for the
это скажем желание
Russians to have a bad time  it’s like a
чтобы у Россиян было плохо оно как бы
habit and for example, when you
стоит привычкой и например ты когда
read, for example, there are shellings in Belgorod And
читаешь например в Белгороде обстрелы И
you’re like Wow, this lifts the mood. I
ты такой Вау это поднимает настроение Я
’ll say more, I’ll say more. You know
больше скажу я больше скажу Ты знаешь
this about the Tajik tour,
вот это про гастроли
yes, you say I know a little, what do you
пра да говоришь знаю немножко как ты
think, that’s what I felt
думаешь вот какое у меня было ощущение
from that  that I learned this news I hope the
от того что я узнал эту новость Надеюсь
first VKI was suffering for the victims for the
первое вки было страдание к жертвам к
families of the victims No, you don’t know that I
семьям жертв Нет не полу знаешь что
immediately read how many died, about 155,
сразу читал сколько погибших около 155
how many no, and then it was that
на сколько нет а потом оно что оно
at first it didn’t reach 100, will it be a hundred
сначала до 100 не доходило будет сотка
or not, I thought really, well, I honestly say
или нет думал реально ну я честно говорю
I think damn it will be
я думаю блин будет
100 Well, my friend and I were drinking coffee, we were talking, we were talking about
сотка Ну по мы с другом пили кофе
whether it would reach 100,
общались рассуждали дотянет ли до сотки
I said that it would last, I said that
я говорил что дотянет я говорил что
the authorities, in any case, first reduce them,
власти они по-любому сначала уменьшаю
then like he said that there will not be
потом типа он говорил что не будет
100, you know, I can
сотки 150 было знаешь вот могу тебе
tell you such an
рассказать такой
example. Well, of course  I don’t know how it’s possible
пример Ну конечно не знаю как можно ли
to compare like that. My mother, well, we live
так сравнивать У меня мама ну мы живём
in Chelyabinsk, it’s peaceful here, of course,
короче в Челябинске тут конечно мирно
so it’s probably not very How can I
поэтому наверное это не очень Как
say the correct comparison, but she
сказать правильное сравнение но она
helped refugees from the Donetsk region and
помогала беженцам из Донецкой области и
so on who decided to flee to Russia,
так далее которые решили бежать в Россию
helped financially, helped bring things,
помогал финансово помогал вещи привозить
and so on  further in the hotel So, well,
и так далее в отеле Так что Ну как-то
somehow I still found suffering within myself, I
всё-таки находила в себе страдание мне
think you know that when
кажется знаешь что когда продолжается
this hatred continues, when you read
вот эта ненависть когда ты читаешь
the news, you have some kind of
новость у тебя появляется вот какое-то
crap and so on, because of this, only
сра отст и так далее из-за этого только
it multiplies, multiplies, multiplies  and at the expense of
она множится множится множится и за счёт
some such strong people, at the
каких-то Вот таких сильных людей за за
expense of some good intentions, on the contrary,
счёт каких-то добрых побуждений наоборот
this conflict will end And
это конфликт будет заканчиваться И
gradually Nasta You are very cool, I
постепенно Наста Ты очень классно я
thought about it. That is, it
задумался То есть
turns out that refugees in the Donetsk region
получается беженцы в Донецкой области
appeared due to the fact that your mother in
появились из-за того что твоя мама в
the person of Vladimir Putin
лице Владимира Путина
shelled their cities, attacked
обстреливала ихние города напала на
Ukraine and refugees appeared. Well,
Украину и появились беженцы Ну а что а
guess what? there was a flood in the Donetsk
поди беженцы там потоп был в Донецкой
region. Why did refugees come to you
области Ну почему беженцы приехали к вам
in Chelyabinsk?
в Челябинск Что случилось из-за
and
есть война Россия напала на Украину и
refugees appeared,
появились беженцы
yes, that is, you are right, that is correct, that
да то есть тя правильно правильно то
is, your mother As a Citizen of the Russian
есть твоя мама Как Гражданка Российской
Federation Yes, you and others made
Федерации Да ты и другие сделали так
these refugees run away from their
чтобы эти беженцы убежали из своих
homes and mom didn’t look, and Mom still
домов и мама по нет Смотри и Мама ещё
seems like this is hypocritical, I understand, it
те кажется это лицемерно я понял мне
seems to me to talk about such a global  answer,
кажется говорить о такой глобальной отве
I listened to you, listen, it just
я тебя выслушал Послушай просто
turns out that the Russians made sure that
получается россияне сделали так чтобы
these people from Donetsk were deprived of their homes and
эти люди из Донецка лишили своих домов и
fled to some Chelyabinsk, and now
убежали в какой-то Челябинск и теперь
I think that they did Mega good for them, that it’s me
считаю что они сделали Мега добро им что
anymore, they just think that something
это я больше просто считают что-то хотя
at least good needs to be done, you know  It seems to me to
бы доброе нужно сделать да понимаешь мне
talk about such a global
кажется говорить о такой глобальной
responsibility that I am to blame,
ответственности что там я виноват
for example, for the fact that there is a War and so
например за то что идёт Война и так
on. I think this is not entirely
далее Мне кажется это не совсем
correct, so you can simply reach
корректно так просто можно дойти до
some generally absurd degree,
какой-то вообще абсурдной степени
say there you are drinking tea now and
сказать там вот ты пьёшь Сейчас чай а
some child is in  I didn’t drink in Africa
какой-нибудь ребёнок в Африке не попил
Well, that’s nonsense Like saying that I
Ну это же бред Типа так говорить Мне
think it’s
кажется такую глобальную ответственность
not worth attributing such a global responsibility to everyone, to be
всем приписывать не стоит если
honest
честно
really Well, I agree with you in
действительно Ну с тобой сходимся в
principle, well, yes, well, there’s something
принципе в принципе ну как Да ну что-то
in your uh opinion, I think that it’s
в твоём э мнении есть я же думаю что как
kind of
бы
uh from  Children in Africa depend on me, here we are in
ээ от меня зависят дети в афри вот мы
Ukraine, we don’t supply water to Africa, we
Украина не поставляем воду в Африку мы
took their water; in Africa there was running water,
забрали у них воду в Африке был
yes. And for the sake of our tea, we
водопровод да А мы ради нашего чая мы
made a tea plantation there and dried it out in
сделали там чайную плантацию и высушили
Africa, so I agree, you
африкан кидаю поэтому я соглас ты
use a telephone there, I do
пользуешься же телефоном там
n’t know.  no, of course
какие-нибудь не знаю нет естественно
you can make a connection some
можно связь провести какие-нибудь
African children got
африканские дети добыли для батареи
some kind of lithium for the battery and so on Nickel there it’s still
какой-нибудь лити и так далее Никель там
possible to make a connection
это же можно всё равно связь провести
Agree, I understand yes In short, I understand I
Согласись понял да Короче я я понял Я
just My family never voted for Putin
просто Моя семья за Путина никогда не
so I don’t  I know you don’t have it there, but I
су я я ж не знаю у тебя же нету там вот
can’t understand as a Russian
я не могу по россиянину понять
I didn’t vote, but for me it
голосовала не голосовал вот для меня это
doesn’t matter I have a passport of the Russian
неважно есть паспорт Российской
Federation Yes, there are people who are
Федерации Да вот есть люди которые
Russians, but they are fighting against Russia or
россияне но Они воюют против России или
they went to Europe and somehow help
они выехали в Европу и как-то помогают
Ukraine, then I understand  yes And so
Украине вот тогда понимаю да А так
it turns out, well, Russia steals children from the
получается ну Россия ворует детей с
territory of Ukrainian Ukraine. Yes, they
территории украинской Украины Да
deport them to the Russian Federation,
депортируют их в Российскую Федерацию
then they are adopted there. No, this is cruel. I
потом их там усыновляют нет это жестоко
agree, I’m not talking about such examples there
согласен я не про такие примеры там
when it’s with me, it seems to me that let’s
когда се при я как бы мне кажется что
say you’re a very good psychologist,
скажем ты вот очень хороший психолог
you see, you can  to find there you need to
видишь ты можешь найти там тебе нужно
go not to chat roulette and
как бы ходить не в чат рулетку и с
talk to Ukrainians, but go out, for example, in
украинцами говорить А выйти например в
your city, go to the military registration and enlistment office and
своём городе прийти в военкомат и
say, for example, this is how you know how to
сказать например вот так как ты умеешь
say that look, we still seem to be
говорить что смотрите мы же всё-таки как
doing it wrong, you know this in your mind.  the
бы неправильно делаем вот тынь уме это
same as some kind of act of
знаешь То же самое как какой-нибудь акт
self-immolation, it’s useless and it’s not easy to just
самосожжения бесполезно и не просто
walk and tell people
просто или ходить и вот людям говорить
that
что
look, we shouldn’t fight there.
смотрите как бы мы не должны там воевать
Well, just walk. You can do it like that normally, don’t
Ну просто ходить Ты можешь так нормально
tell me that you love
ты мне вот мне бе говори что любите
Russians, everything has already risen for me
россиян всё у меня уже конли поднялось
completely It seems to me that the best thing I can do is that I can
полностью Мне кажется лучшее что я могу
do this to my close friends there for
сделать это своим близким друзьям там
future children to somehow teach such ideas
детям будущем такие идеи как-то
and to go out on the streets, look to me, a
преподать а выходить на улиц мне смотри
Ukrainian, you won’t be able to prove anything,
мне украинцу ты уже ничего не докажешь
everything, look, I’ll
всё у меня смотри у меня полностью
say completely, I’ve had an internal
скажем произошла внутренняя
transformation Yes Energy It’s like
трансформация Да Энергетическая Это как
this  for example, you take the metal, you
Вот например ты возьми металл ты его
melted it all, it’s already melted It’s
расплавил всё он уже расплавился Он
already different, you won’t return this product I’m
уже другой ты не вернёшь это изделие Я
not the same as I was before, I can’t I’m
уже не такой как был раньше я не могу Я
telling you, I tried compassion, so I’m
же говорю я пробовал сострадание вот я
looking at you, you’re a normal person, you
смотрю к тебе ты нормальный человек ты
won’t support Putin, that’s it, but I  I can’t have
не поддержишь Путина всё но я не могу к
compassion for you, but if it’s possible
тебе сострадание я по вот если возможно
in a generation or in a
через поколение или через через
generation, maybe, yes, maybe our children are just
поколение может да может наши дети также
like, for example, look at the Jews who were
как например смотри евреи которых
exterminated by the Germans during the Second World
уничтожали немцы во время Второй мировой
War. Yes, they were. Honestly, what was someone
войны Да им было Честно говоря что там
thinking
думал какой-то
now, a generation later, already there  how the
сейчас через поколение уже там как
Germans will behave, how they IP pokutyu
поведут себ вот немцы как они ИС покутю
They show that they regret it,
Они показывают что они сожалеют об этом
they suffered it financially, and in
они это и материально понесли и в
Russian society now this is not present,
российском обществе нету сейчас этого
firstly, it’s still early, yes yes, that’s why I’m
во-первых это ещ ран да да поэтому я
telling you honestly Look, you’re a
тебе честно говорю Смотри ты вот
normal kid, everything but if tomorrow  I
нормальный пацан всё но если завтра я
’ll see that, for example, in Chelyabinsk, in
увижу что например на Челябинску у вас в
Chelyabinsk, there was a meteor there a couple of
Челябинске же был там метеори вот пару
years ago, a dozen years ago, 10 years ago, and what
лет десяток лет назад 10 назад а это
if a meteorite falls, stupidly,
если вот покаже упадёт метеорит тупо
in short, it will blow away half of the chalyabinsk Yes, I
короче там пол челябы снесёт Да я даже
won’t even remember that you were good I’ll be
не вспомню что ты был хороший Я буду
glad that I’m in Chelyabinsk  in short, a meteorite
радоваться что в челябе короче метеорит
because
потому что
I’m like with Orsk. I think that in Orsk, too,
я как с орском Я думаю что в Орске тоже
a lot of good people were flooded, a
затопило очень много хороших людей очень
lot of good people voted there, that’s
много хороших людей там голосовали вот
all who were not interested in politics, they’re
все кто не интересовался политикой они
all their houses, too, in short, this is right up to the
все вот ихние дома тоже короче по это по
dams. Well, how do I understand that they
самую дамб Ну как бы я понимаю что они
outside of politics I understand that they
вне политики Я понимаю что они с этим
may not
как бы может там и против Путина не
have voted against Putin with this. Well, for me they are. Well, this is a war,
голосовали Ну для меня они Ну это война
the more problems there are in Russia, the faster
чем больше в России проблем тем быстрее
this war becomes. When tomorrow there are
становится эта война Когда завтра будут
forest and steppe fires, I will understand
пожары лесные и степные я буду понимать
that it’s good when it’s there  I don’t know
что это хорошо когда будет там не знаю
if the Sayano Shushinskaya HS will break through, there
это прорвёт Саяно Шушинская ГС
will be a catastrophe, I will
катастрофа будет я буду
really be afraid of
реально бо
earthquakes
землетрясений
in it somehow
ней како
or in society so that What do you want to
или в обществе чтобы Что ты хочешь
say is that there will be some kind of
сказать чтобы какой-то переворот
social revolution in Russia, the thing is that exchange
общественный был в России дело в том
never, such things
чтом обм никогда вот такие вещи никогда
can never be understood when they will happen, for example,
нельзя понять когда они будут например
who  -could have predicted that Prigozhin
кто-то мог предугадать что Пригожин
would go to Moscow Yes, no one, no one For everyone,
пойдёт на Москву Да никто никто Для всех
it was a shock, all the same, for example, someone
это было шок всё также например кто-то
could say that the USSR would collapse in 2 days,
мог сказать что СССР распадётся за 2 дня
no, that is, such things happen,
нет то есть такие вещи они бывают
some kind of arrives, As they say, a black
прилетает какой-то Как говорится чёрный
swan and that’s
лебедь и всё
it.  I’ll just tell you as a chess player,
То есть я просто как шахматист тебе
there’s this concept of position,
скажу вот есть такое понятие позиция у
you don’t have a solution right now, but you’re
тебя нету сейчас вот решения но ты
improving your position. Yes, somewhere there’s a
улучшает свою позицию Да там где-то
pawn in the center, there’s someone else’s knight on the edge, you’ve
пешки в центр там чужого коня на край
captured a line there for yourself for rook groves,
отбил там линию себе для лади рощи у
your position is improving and sooner or
тебя улучшается позиция и рано или
later  it turns into some kind of
поздно она переходит в какие-то
combinational actions, and here, that is, the
комбинационные действия так и тут то
situation has worsened in Orsk. There,
есть там ухудшилась в Орске ситуация Там
oil refineries there, the
нефтеперерабатывающие заводы там там
general situation is being shaken, that’s all,
общая ситуация расшатываются вот и всё
somewhere it will shoot, I understand that
где-то оно выстрелит понимаю что
and so here I am, I’m communicating with you now,
а так вот у меня я вот с тобой сейчас
you see with me  zero regret no
общаюсь видишь у меня ноль сожаления нет
So I understand you’re a normal guy
Вот я понимаю ты вот нормальный парень
like For peace for Kiev like yes that’s what
типа За мир за Киев типа да вот как
we say yes Well I’m like zero Well for
говорит у нас да Ну я типа ноль Ну у за
Kiev Primor Well I don’t support which
Киев Примор Ну это я же не поддерживаю
side there It’s a joke as a name
сторону там какую Это прикол как имя
like the Chechen name Zamir for  Kiev type A
типа чеченское имя Замир за Киев типа А
understood everything that like that guy who at the
всё понял что типа что чувак который в
Moscow airport met this
аэропорту Москвы встречал э этого
Chechen named Zamir Kiev he didn’t
чеченца по фамилии Замир Киев у него не
have a chance to give it well
было шансов дать его ну
Maybe then it’s worth leaving for example with your
Может стоит тогда уезжать например с
families just to avoid
семьями просто ради того чтобы не
getting into this goth that you want and to
попадать в это готе что вы хоте и к
Ukrainians too, that is, so as not to
украинцам тоже то есть чтобы например не
leave for example Well, to Europe or in
уезжать к примеру Ну в Европу или в
Russia anywhere with families so as
России куда угодно семьями чтобы
not to suffer from the war, thank you, that is, everything
не страдать от войны спасибо то есть всё
that you gave birth to was offered to us Run away from
что ты родил это предложил нам Беги из
Ukraine Well, no, how is it possible not to get
Украины Ну нет как возможно не получить
such an injury and
такую травму и
Yes, you are just [ __ ] awesome  in short
Да ты просто охуенный короче
Motiva
Мотива
Bela Maybe then from Ukraine Yes, in short, don’t
бела Может тогда с Украины Да короче не
suffer, but I’m not fighting in Ukraine
страдать только я же не воюю на Украине
Why did you
Зачем помог
help stop the
помог остановить
louse from becoming a louse so that
воша становлению во ша к тому чтобы дети
your children and so on there and you don’t get
твои и так далее там и ты не получили
injured and can develop and continue to live
травмы и смогли развиваться и жить
well, for example, at least  in another
дальше хорошо например хотя бы в другой
country Well, just or what to do What is the
стране Ну просто либо что делать Какая
alternative for you to
альтернатива альтернатива тебе
go Well, okay, I don’t know why you’re offended
пойти Ну ладно не знаю зачем ты обиделся
I’m not offended I’m just
Я не обиделся Я просто я
laughing I’m saying this as an option in order to
ршу я говорю это как вариант для того
develop normally despite the
чтобы нормально развиваться несмотря на
difficult situation as an option You couldn’t
тяжёлую ситуацию как вариант Ты не мог
go well you  you can’t be an insult you
пойти ну ты не можешь бе оскорбление ты
can’t have a constructive conversation it’s
не можешь конструктивно вести беседу это
constructive I’m constructive I
конструктивно я конструктивно Я
’m asking I didn’t send you I’m pre You
спрашиваю Я же тебя не послал Я пре Ты
couldn’t go well you understand that
не мог бы пойти ну ты понимаешь то что
this is an insult like You
это оскорбление типа Ты
can And I’m asking Morova means an
може А я спрашиваю морова значит
insult No this is a question you could
оскорбление Нет это вопрос ты мог бы
go
пойти
Okay,
Хорошо
let's be offended by the
давай обиделся
alternatives, put plus who who
альтернатив поставьте плюс кто кому
deserved it I'm father and drone Vis for
сподобалось я отец ан дроне Вис на
a conversation that is, they attacked us damn it And
беседу то есть они На нас напали блин И
all that he was able to
всё что он короче смог
give birth to in short, you can, in short, with your relatives in
родить може тебе короче с родными в
Europe, subscribe to my Telegram right
Европу подпишись на мий Telegram прямо
now, the axis of wine and
зараз ось вин а
popk tse duzhe  and really YouTube has occupied
попк це дуже и дуже ливо YouTube заня
us through skarg or in your ban and so
нас через скарг ор в твый бан и дуже
much video I won’t show people sometimes I won’t
багато вдео не показу людям вчасно не
show information about streams. That’s why
показуе информация про стрими Тому для
we need Mali
того щоб ми Мали оперативний звязок
to write an operational link right away and while there in telegra okm video also
пишиться прямо зараз а пок там в телегра
tezh tsikava and korisna
окм вдео ще теж цикава и корисна
information and  pon vama sing opera link
информация и пон вама пой опера звязок
nezalezhno in togo chi show you about it
незалежно в того чи покаже вам про це
YouTube Glory to Ukraine letter
YouTube Слава Украине пись